<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<doc>
	<enum name="FbTransactionOptions" namespace="FirebirdSql.Data.Firebird">
		<overview>
			<summary>
			Specifies Firebird transactions specific options that can be used with
			<see cref="FbConnection.BeginTransaction()">BeginTransaction</see>.
			</summary>
		</overview>
		<field name="Consistency">
			<summary>
			Table locking transaction model.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="Concurrency">
			<summary>
			High concurrency transaction with acceptable
			consistency. The use of this parameter takes full advantage
			multi-generational transaction model.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="Shared">
			<summary>
			Concurrent, shared access of a specified table among all transactions. 
			Used with LockRead and Lock Write options to establish the lock option.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="Protected">
			<summary>
			Concurrent, restricted access of a specified table.
			Used with LockRead and Lock Write options to establish the lock option.		
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="Exclusive">
			<summary>
			Exclusive access of a specified table.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="Wait">
			<summary>
			Lock resolution specifies that the transaction is to wait until locked
			resources are released before retrying an operation.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="NoWait">
			<summary>
			Lock resolution specifies that the transaction is not to wait for locks to be
			released, but instead, a lock conflict error should be returned immediately.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="Read">
			<summary>
			Read-only access mode that allows a transaction only to select data.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="Write">
			<summary>
			Read-write access mode of that allows a transaction to select, insert,
			update, and delete table data.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="LockRead">
			<summary>
			Read only access of a specified table. 
			Used with Shared, Protected and Exclusive options to establish the lock option.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="LockWrite">
			<summary>
			Read/write access of a specified table.
			Used with Shared, Protected and Exclusive options to establish the lock option.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="ReadCommitted">
			<summary>
			High throughput, high concurrency transaction that can read changes
			committed by other concurrent transactions. 
			The use of this parameter takes full advantage multi-generational transaction model.		
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="Autocommit">
		</field>	
		<field name="RecVersion">
			<summary>
			Enables an ReadCommitted transaction to read the most recently
			committed version of a record even if other, uncommitted versions are
			pending.
			</summary>
		</field>	
		<field name="NoRecVersion">
			<summary>
			Enables an ReadCommitted transaction to read only the latest
			committed version of a record. If an uncommitted version of a record is
			pending and Wait is also specified, then the transaction waits for
			the pending record to be committed or rolled back before proceeding.
			Otherwise, a lock conflict error is reported at once.
			</summary>			
		</field>	
		<field name="RestartRequest">
		</field>	
		<field name="NoAutoUndo">
		</field>	
	</enum>
</doc>